<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>The Tin Feather (Posts about introduction)</title><link>http://tinfeathers.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://tinfeathers.org/categories/cat_introduction.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2019 &lt;a href="mailto:x6495ed@gmail.com"&gt;Feather Tin&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 19:58:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>On the Shoulders of Giants</title><link>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-the-shoulders-of-giants/</link><dc:creator>Feather Tin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;strong&gt;If I have seen further it is by standing on the shoulders of Giants.&lt;/strong&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;—Isaac Newton, 1675&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This well known quotation expresses an idea that lies at the foundations of the
scientific tradition, mathematics, and open source software, three of the top
intellectual achievements of the human species. Yet in literature it goes unused.
The scientist, mathematician, and programmer readily appropriate and re-purpose
ideas from our predecessors while most authors seem to aim for an entirely
personal creative work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\iota\)&lt;/span&gt; am not an author and this is nothing so formal as a "work of
literature." Yet &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\iota\)&lt;/span&gt; do have ideas to share and know communication requires
shared semantics. These may be found in a set of mathematical axioms, a computer
programming language, but also in a popular movie, in song lyrics, and within
comedy. In the name of pragmatism and due to the urgency of the task at hand &lt;span class="math"&gt;\(\iota\)&lt;/span&gt;
will make free use of all these sources, the profound to the profane, confident
of their effect, with respect, and in hopeful anticipation of their originators'
approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"&lt;strong&gt;I am Jack's betrayed sense of privacy.&lt;/strong&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="attribution"&gt;—after the Narrator, &lt;strong&gt;Fight Club&lt;/strong&gt;,
Chuck Palahnuik&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-the-shoulders-of-giants/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 19:47:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On Finding a Voice</title><link>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-finding-a-voice/</link><dc:creator>Feather Tin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current presentation of this material is still evolving. It is more
important to capture these ideas as the Muse offers them than it is to polish
their presentation. A few words of disclaimer and apology are in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-finding-a-voice/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-finding-a-voice/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 23:46:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On the Idea of the Tin Feather</title><link>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-the-idea-of-the-tin-feather/</link><dc:creator>Feather Tin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tin Feathers has rapidly evolved through multiple stages in the course of the
first serious consideration of the idea, far from the joke with which it began.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-the-idea-of-the-tin-feather/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-the-idea-of-the-tin-feather/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:27:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On Pronouns</title><link>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-pronouns/</link><dc:creator>Feather Tin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choice of third-person pronoun is an issue of the modern world that simply did
not exist in my youth. Such issues are, however, orthogonal to the aims of Tin
Feathers. I do feel the need to speak briefly of first-person pronouns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-pronouns/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (1 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-pronouns/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 22:14:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>On the Birth of a Social Conscience</title><link>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-the-birth-of-a-social-conscience/</link><dc:creator>Feather Tin</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;dl class="docutils"&gt;
&lt;dt&gt;The Nobel laureate Bob Dylan sang it better than I will ever be able to say it.&lt;/dt&gt;
&lt;dd&gt;&lt;div class="first last line-block"&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;em&gt;My name it means nothing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="line"&gt;&lt;em&gt;My age it means less.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet precisely because I am no one I presume to speak to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birth is trauma. Kicking and fighting we are brought into this world regardless
of our wishes. So it is with a social conscience. I did not want one. I do not
know what to do with it; how to nurture it. Life was decidedly easier before,
but such has fallen to me and I would be remiss not to give it voice. So the
Zeitgeist speaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tin foil hat is a known symbol in our collective semiology. It captures the
suspicion, mistrust, and paranoia all in technology share regarding that with
which we forge our living. We know these tools all too well; we are their smiths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money, power, influence. Fake news, election tampering. Fortunes made and
fortunes lost. The rest of the world is slowly awakening to what we have long
been aware of, but hiding from. What we tried to laugh off with a tin hat joke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not know how to fix this world. I know only that the first step is to
acknowledge the problem. That said, we need a forum for discussion, a common
store of information and raw data. We are problem solvers, after all. Can our
"many eyes" and the "wisdom of crowds" solve these problems? We shall see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so the Tin Feather. I wear the first in my hat to admit the problem and to
foster conversation. &lt;strong&gt;To protest surveillance capitalism and invasive data
harvesting.&lt;/strong&gt; I lay before you not a gauntlet, but merely a feather. Now take it
up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tin feather… when a tin hat is too heavy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tin-feather/TinFeather/master/images/tin_feather_on_hat.jpeg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tin feather on hat" class="thumbnail" src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/tin-feather/TinFeather/master/images/tin_feather_on_hat.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>http://tinfeathers.org/posts/on-the-birth-of-a-social-conscience/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 21:42:34 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>